Register of the W. Sheldon Ridge Papers, 1905-1939
Hoover Institution Archives
W. Sheldon Ridge Papers,
1905-1939
47017
Ridge, W. Sheldon (William Sheldon), b. 1875
14 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize folder (7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Clippings and notes, relating to political, social, and economic conditions in China and to Chinese history, foreign relations, and civilization.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1947.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
China.
Series Description
- Subject File, 1918-1939. (Box No. 1.)
  Correspondence, memoranda, position papers, reports, and printed matter arranged alphabetically by subject
- Clippings and Notes, 1918-1939. (Box No. 2-14.)
  Personal reference file of Ridge, whose arrangement was kept here
- Oversize Material (Map Case)
  Political cartoons (in Chinese), charts of the 1910 census data, maps and posters on the subjects of opium, the Shantung flooding, etc.
Container List
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1939
  - Chai-tung - Coal (Box 1.)
  - Chin Yun-peng
  - China - Foreign relations
    - General
    - Japan - Loans made by Japan
  - Opium
    - Correspondence of Ridge
    - International Anti-Opium Association file
      - Correspondence
      - Memoranda
      - Position papers
    - Reports
    - Miscellaneous
  - Ridge - Personal file
  - Russia
  - Salt
  - Stevens, Frederick. Statement to newspapers on his position as representative of the American group of the Consortium, 1921 January 21
  - Sun Yat-sen
  - Yellow River. Report by C. G. W. Finje van Salvadera on the improvement of the Hwang-ho, or Yellow River
  - Yuan Ko-ting, Crown Prince
  - Yuan Shi-k'ai
- CLIPPINGS AND NOTES, 1918-1939
  - Biographical file of notable Chinese and foreigners, 1918-1920 (Box 2.)
  - War file, 1918-1939 (Box 3.)
  - Subject file (Box 4-5.)
    - 1918-1919
    - 1918-1919 (Box 6-7.)
    - 1920-1922 (Box 8.)
    - Post 1922, mostly 1933-1939 (Box 9-11.)
  - Opium file (Box 12.)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13.)
    - Clippings arranged chronologically by month
    - Clippings arranged by subject (Box 14.)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - Political cartoons (in Chinese), charts of the 1910 census data, maps and posters on the subjects of opium, the Shantung flooding, etc. (Box Map Case)